{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Oxidation of SO2 to SO3 is favoured by", "opta": "low temperature and low pressure.", "optb": "low temperature and high pressure.", "optc": "high temperature and low pressure.", "optd": "high temperature and high pressure.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gun powder,  which is an explosive comprises of charcoal,  sulphur and", "opta": "glycerene", "optb": "salt petre", "optc": "nitro glycerene", "optd": "dynamite", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Starting raw material for the manufacture of alum is", "opta": "alumina", "optb": "gypsum", "optc": "bauxite", "optd": "ammonium bicarbonate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Salt cake is chemically represented by", "opta": "Na2SO4", "optb": "CaSO4.H2O", "optc": "MgSO4", "optd": "BaSO4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following sugars is the sweetest?", "opta": "Glucose", "optb": "Fructose", "optc": "Sucrose", "optd": "Lactose", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Paper pulp produced by kraft/sulphate process is", "opta": "bleached easily", "optb": "dull white in color", "optc": "strong fibrous", "optd": "dark colored", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Claude process of gas liquefaction employs", "opta": "merely compression of gas beyond its critical pressure.", "optb": "Joule-Thomson expansion cooling.", "optc": "heat exchange with colder stream.", "optd": "adiabatic expansion against a piston or in a turbine.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The main use of HCl is in the", "opta": "drilling of petroleum wells and pickling of steel sheets.", "optb": "manufacture of cationic detergent.", "optc": "treatment of spent fuel of nuclear reactor.", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The gasification reaction represented by, C + H2O = CO + H2,  is a/an __________ reaction.", "opta": "exothermic", "optb": "endothermic", "optc": "catalytic", "optd": "autocatalytic", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Viscose rayon is chemically", "opta": "cellulose nitrate", "optb": "regenerated cellulose nitrate", "optc": "cellulose acetate", "optd": "regenerated cellulose acetate", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All enzymes are made of", "opta": "fats", "optb": "carbohydrates", "optc": "proteins", "optd": "amino acids", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The combustion reaction,  C + O2 = CO2,  is", "opta": "exothermic", "optb": "endothermic", "optc": "autocatalytic", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Styrene is produced from ethyl benzene by the process of", "opta": "dehydrogenation", "optb": "oxidation", "optc": "alkylation", "optd": "dehydration", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gelatine which is a nitrogenous organic protein is obtained by the hydrolysis of", "opta": "callagen", "optb": "tannin", "optc": "molasses", "optd": "carbohydrate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The chamber process is", "opta": "preferred over contact process for producing 98 to 100% H2SO4 and various oleums.", "optb": "non-catalytic and operates only on pyrites.", "optc": "a batch process for directly producing high strength (98 to 100%) H2SO4.", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sucrose content in the raw juice extracted from sugar cane is about __________ percent.", "opta": "1 - 2", "optb": "15 - 20", "optc": "50 - 60", "optd": "80 - 85", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fusel oil is a/an", "opta": "essential oil.", "optb": "extract from medicinal herbs.", "optc": "mixture of higher molecular weight alcohols (a by-product obtained during production of alcohol from molasses).", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Styrene-butadiene-rubber (SBR)  as compared to natural rubber has", "opta": "Poorer tensile strength.", "optb": "poorer resistance to oxidation.", "optc": "greater amount of heat build-up under heavy loading.", "optd": "all (a),  (b) and (c).", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Co-efficient of thermal expansion of glass is decreased by the addition of __________ during its manufacture.", "opta": "CaO", "optb": "MnO2", "optc": "ZnO", "optd": "FeS", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The catalyst used in the manufacture of DDT (from chloral and chlorobenzene) is", "opta": "dilute H2SO4", "optb": "oleum", "optc": "ultraviolet light", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Haemoglobin is a/an", "opta": "amino acid", "optb": "biological catalyst", "optc": "protein", "optd": "enezyme", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Epoxy resin", "opta": "is a good adhesive.", "optb": "is an elastomer.", "optc": "cannot be used for surface coatings.", "optd": "is a polyester.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Concentration of NaOH solution produced by mercury electrolytic cell is about __________ percent.", "opta": "10", "optb": "25", "optc": "50", "optd": "98", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the most adverse factor challenging the choice of mercury electrolytic cell process for the production of caustic soda?", "opta": "High cost of mercury.", "optb": "High specific gravity of mercury.", "optc": "Non-availability of high purity mercury.", "optd": "Pollution of water stream by mercury.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Esterification reaction produces", "opta": "detergent", "optb": "vanaspati", "optc": "soap", "optd": "mercaptans", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Wood charcoal is used for decolouration of sugar,  because  it __________ the  coloured materials.", "opta": "adsorbs", "optb": "oxidises", "optc": "reduces", "optd": "converts", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Producer gas consists mainly of", "opta": "CO,  CO2 N2, H2", "optb": "CO, H2", "optc": "H2,  CH4", "optd": "C2H2, CO2, H2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Neoprene is the trade name of", "opta": "polyurathane", "optb": "phenol formaldehyde", "optc": "polychloroprene", "optd": "styrene-butadiene rubber", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hard water", "opta": "does not affect the lather formation by soap.", "optb": "is not unfit for drinking purpose.", "optc": "pollutes the water stream.", "optd": "all (a),  (b) and (c).", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an organo-metal-lic compound ?", "opta": "Isopropyl alcohol", "optb": "Tetra-ethyl lead", "optc": "Zeolite", "optd": "Cumene", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sulphur addition in soap is done to", "opta": "improve the soap texture.", "optb": "cure pimples & dandruff.", "optc": "fasten lather formation.", "optd": "increase its cleansing action.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Phosphate rock is a raw material for the manufacture of", "opta": "phosphoric acid", "optb": "phosphorous", "optc": "superphosphates", "optd": "all (a),  (b) and (c)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mineral oils (e.g. petroleum oils) are preferred over fatty oils (e.g. mustard oil,  ghee,  tallow,  palm oil,  olive oil etc.) as a lubricant due to its", "opta": "poor oxidation stability and high gum forming tendency.", "optb": "greater tendency of decomposition at elevated temperature.", "optc": "hydrolysis tendency in presence of water.", "optd": "all (a),  (b) and (c).", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a raw material used for the manufacture of ordinary glass?", "opta": "Iron oxide", "optb": "Soda ash", "optc": "Limestone", "optd": "Silica", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Esterification reaction", "opta": "produces soap.", "optb": "is reversible.", "optc": "is a reaction between an alcohol and an organic acid.", "optd": "all (a),  (b) and (c).", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In sulphate pulp manufacture,  the pressure and temperature in the digestor is", "opta": "10 atm.,  800 \u00b0C", "optb": "10 atm.,  170-180\u00b0C", "optc": "1 atm.,  170 - 180\u00b0C", "optd": "l atm., 800\u00b0C", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Zeolite removes both temporary as well as permanent hardness of water by precipitating calcium and magnesium present in water as insoluble zeolites. Used zeolite is regenerated by flushing with the solution of", "opta": "calcium sulphate", "optb": "sodium chloride", "optc": "sodium sulphate", "optd": "magnesium chloride.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick out the endothermic reaction out of the following.", "opta": "C+O2 = CO", "optb": "CO + 3H2 = CH4 + H2O", "optc": "CaCO3 = CaO + CO2", "optd": "CO +O2 = CO2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pasteurisation of milk means", "opta": "removal of fatty and albuminous substance from it.", "optb": "killing of organisms present in it by heating it at controlled temperature without changing its natural characteristics.", "optc": "inhibiting the growth of micro-organisms without killing them.", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fusion of bauxite and __________ produces  high alumina cement.", "opta": "alum", "optb": "limestone", "optc": "coke", "optd": "quartz", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ process is used for the manufacture of sodium carbonate by ammonia soda process.", "opta": "Ostwald's", "optb": "Bosch", "optc": "Solvay", "optd": "Haber's", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Polycaprolactum is commercially known as", "opta": "nylon-6", "optb": "nylon-66", "optc": "dacron", "optd": "rayon", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Frasch process is for", "opta": "making oxygen", "optb": "producing helium", "optc": "mining sulphur", "optd": "making nitrogen", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Very fine suspended and colloidal impurities are removed from water by a process called", "opta": "sedimentation", "optb": "coagulation", "optc": "disinfection", "optd": "softening", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pitch (a product of coal tar distillation) is always mixed with creosote oil,  when it is to be burnt in a burner,  because", "opta": "its calorific value is very less.", "optb": "tar neutralises the residual acids present in pitch.", "optc": "it reduces viscosity and imparts fluidity for its transportation through pipelines at economic pressure drop.", "optd": "all (a),  (b) and (c).", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the main reducing agent during production of iron from iron ore in a blast furnace ?", "opta": "C", "optb": "CO", "optc": "CO2", "optd": "H2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The drug used in contraceptives is", "opta": "sulphadizene", "optb": "mestranol", "optc": "methyl salicylate", "optd": "pencillin", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Raw materials used for producing __________ cement does not contain iron oxide.", "opta": "waterproof", "optb": "slag", "optc": "white", "optd": "pozzolan", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the Lurgi coal gasifier", "opta": "coking coals cannot be used.", "optb": "low carbon conversion efficiency is achieved.", "optc": "entrainment of solids is higher.", "optd": "large quantity of coal can be processed.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Neon gas is", "opta": "flammable in nature.", "optb": "used in color discharge tube.", "optc": "filled in lamps having tungsten filament.", "optd": "all (a),  (b) and (c).", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}